OSCAR LOPEZ

Seattle, WA ● (478) 290-7588 ● OSCARLLOPEZ98@gmail.com ● https://oscarllopez98.github.io

I've been a QA Engineer for 2+ years. My core strength was spotting problems before they happened and when errors did occur, digging deep to find out why, ensuring a smooth user experience. I'm looking for my next challenge as a Software Engineer at a fast-paced company with smart, motivated people. I'm knowledgeable in frontend (JavaScript, C++, SQL), as well as Java, Swift and Mobile App Development, and have a passion for growing my problem solving, building, and communication skills. I'm currently working on my AWS Certified Developer - Associate certificate and building fitness product experiences in my personal time.

EXPERIENCE

AMAZON - PRIME Seattle, WA

Quality Assurance Engineer

Jun 2021 - Dec 2023

Led cross-functional teams on Amazon Prime to automate testing, streamline processes, and ensure quality across multiple high-revenue marketplaces with a growth mindset.

- Led a collaborative QA initiative for a mission-critical project spanning 5 cross-functional teams, leading to a unified
 test strategy including issue identification, log analysis and issue escalation, 300+ mobile app test cases, and
 resolving 30+ critical bugs. Ensured smooth international marketplace launches and communicated best practices.
- Implemented Java, Selenium, and POM to automate 640+ test cases in 20 countries, reducing testing time by 50% and minimizing manual intervention by 90%. Rotated on call as needed.
- Maintained a robust regression test suite for 10 upsell locations, bolstering functionality, reliability, and CI/CD pipeline support across 20+ marketplaces. Collaborated with developers to fix bugs and rerun regression tests.
- Developed and implemented an impactful AWS microservice extension which integrated with existing test automation resulting in the near-elimination of manual effort across 20+ marketplaces.

RAMSEY CENTER, UNIVERSITY OF GEORGIA

Athens, GA

Drove process improvement using Python web scraping to optimize gym operations used by 5K+ members.

Facility Tech Program Assistant

Feb 2019 - Dec 2020

• Identified a process issue and built a Python script to web scrape machine parts data from vendor websites, successfully creating a centralized location and optimizing process by 75%.

Facility Technician

Oct 2017 - Jan 2019

 Applied advanced solutions to fix machines by working with Facility Technician Program Assistant, identifying and asking management for additional training, and documenting solutions.

NASA HEADQUARTERS Washington, D.C.

Co-developed a new onboarding website significantly improving employee onboarding.

Mission Support Web Development Intern

Jun 2017 - Aug 2017

- Collaborated with a team of 3 interns to gather requirements, propose, and develop a software solution to shorten the Office of the Chief Financial Officer's onboarding process using Confluence.
- Implemented 2 web pages by documenting user needs, organizing information, and testing for bugs.

EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS

AMAZON WEB SERVICES, Certified Cloud Practitioner **THE UNIVERSITY OF GEORGIA,** B.S. Computer Science

Athens, GA

HOPE Scholar, Code2040 Fellow

Dec 2020

SOFTWARE PROJECTS

Stride Personal Fitness iOS Mobile App (In Progress)

- Use Case: An iOS app allowing me to track my workouts and their progress easily and intuitively.
- Skills: MVVM architecture, SQLite database table design, UML diagrams, Figma, Xcode and Swift

TrophyTeam Fitness Tracker Android Mobile App

- Use Case: An Android app allowing exercisers to track cardio workouts in a user-friendly way.
- Skills: Android Studio, Java, XML, and Google Firebase

E-Commerce Movie Website

• Use: A website displaying and booking current movies, allowing admin privileges, and storing user payment data. Skills: Scrum methodologies, Java, and MySQL

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION